Polymorphism is a feature of inheritance that
ポリモーフィズム（多態性）は継承の機能で
allows classes to have more than one type.
クラスに複数の型を受け入れさせることができます
Within an inheritance hierarchy
継承の階層内において
any child class can be said to be a parent class.
子クラスは常に親クラスと is-a 関係にあります
This means that any time a base class is needed
これは基底クラスが必要なときいつでも
a derived class can be used in it's place.
代わりに派生クラスが使えるということです
Let's say we have a game that uses an inheritance
たとえば次に示すような継承階層のゲームがあるとしましょう
hierarchy where Orc and Goblin are derived
Orc と Goblin の親として Enemy があり
from Enemy, which in turn is derived from Humanoid.
Enemy の親に Humanoid があるという構造です
One thing you might want to do is create a collection of
ここでシーン中の全 Enemy オブジェクトの
all the enemy objects in the scene.
コレクションを作る必要ができたとします
Rather than having 2 collections, 1 for
これにはコレクションを 2 つ作るという手もあります
all the Orcs and 1 for all the Goblins,
ひとつは Orc もうひとつが Goblinですね
you could have 1 collection of enemy objects
しかしここでは Orc オブジェクトと Goblin オブジェクトを
that both Orc objects and Goblin objects
要素として持つコレクション 1 つに
could be elements of.
することが可能です
Similarly, if you also had a player class
またもし同じように Humanoid を継承する
that inherited from Humanoid then you
Player クラスがあるならば さらに
could create a collection of all of the humanoid
シーン内の Humanoid オブジェクト すなわち
objects in a scene and it could contain all Orcs,
Orc・Goblin・Player すべてを含めることも
Goblins and Players.
可能なわけです
Polymorphism also works for things like
ポリモーフィズムはまた関数のパラメーターのような場合にも
function parameters.
活用できます
Consider the OnTrigger functions.
たとえば OnTrigger 関数
Generally they have a collider parameter
通常ここでは Collider パラメーター
which is usually called something like Other.
一般的には other のようなものが使われます
Game objects do not have a collider component
ゲームオブジェクトは Collider コンポーネントを持たず
on them, however they could have a box collider,
代わりに BoxCollider・SphereCollider
sphere collider, mesh collider or something similar.
MeshCollider などを持ちます
When the OnTrigger functions are called
そして OnTrigger 関数が呼び出されるとき
we don't know which type of collider is being used/
どの種類のコライダーが使用されているのかは分かりません
In fact, each object's specific collider is
実際 関数はオブジェクト毎に個別に
parsed in to the function.
コライダーをパースしています
Since all of these different colliders inherit functions
各種コライダーはいずれも Collider 親クラスから関数を
from the collider parent class any of them will work.
継承しているので どれでも動作するのです
It is important to know that the opposite is not possible.
ここでは  逆は不可能であることはしっかり覚えておきましょう
Using our previous example
先の例で言えば
an Orc is an enemy
「Orc は Enemy である」（is-a 関係）は正でも
but an enemy is not an Orc.
「Enemy は Orc である」は誤りなのです
You cannot have something expecting a child class
子クラスが予期されている場面で
and give it a parent class.
親クラスを渡すことはできないのです
One slightly clever use of polymorphism
さてポリモーフィズムの賢い使い方のひとつに
involves constructors and object references.
コンストラクターとオブジェクト参照を使う方法があります
You can declare an object of a base class type and
基底クラス型のオブジェクトを宣言したあと
then call the constructor of one of it's derived classes.
派生クラスのコンストラクターは呼び出せます
This is because the variable reference is expecting
これは変数の参照が基底クラスの型を
something of the base classes type
予期していて子クラスのコンストラクターは
and the constructor of the child class creates
何らかの派生型を
something of a derived type.
作るためです
If this seems confusing just remember
この部分がわかりにくい場合は
that child class is a parent class
子クラスは親クラスである
therefore this conversion works
だからこの変換は機能すると覚えましょう
and is a process known as upcasting.
なお このプロセスはアップキャストと呼ばれます
While an object is upcasted it can only
オブジェクトがアップキャストされている状態では
be treated as an object of it's parent class.
そのオブジェクトは親クラスのものとして扱われます
In this example, while ChildClass is upcasted
この例では ChildClass がアップキャストされている間
it can only be treated as a parent class.
親クラスとしてのみ扱われます
This means that only the variables and methods available
つまり ここで使えるのは親クラスの
in the parent class can be used
変数とメソッドだけになるということで
and they will be treated as if they were in
その時親クラスのオブジェクト内に
an object of the parent class
あるかのように扱われるということです
The exception to this is virtual functions,
なお virtual 関数だけは例外で
which will call the most overridden version.
最後にオーバーライドされたバージョンが呼び出されます
For more information about virtual functions
virtual 関数とオーバーライドの
and overriding them see the lesson
詳細については下記リンク先にある
on Overriding linked below.
オーバーライドのレッスンをご覧ください
In order to treat this child class like a child class
ここで ChildClass を子クラスとして扱うには
we need to downcast the ChildClass variable
ChildClass 変数を子クラスの型に
back in to the child class type.
ダウンキャストする必要があります
We do this by enclosing the name
具体的には
of the type in brackets and putting it in front of the variable.
型の名前をカッコで囲み  変数の前に置きます
We can either enclose this in another set of brackets
この他にも さらにカッコで囲んで
and use the .operator to access members
.（ドット）演算子を使ってメンバーにアクセスしたり
or we can create a reference
参照を作って新しいバージョンに
to this new version.
アクセスしたりもできます